[
    {
        "question": "The islands New Britain and New Ireland are part of what country?",
        "answer": "Papua New Guinea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the biggest glacier outside of Antarctica?",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Ireland`s famous Blarney Stone made of?",
        "answer": "Limestone"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you hike Hadrian`s wall?",
        "answer": "England"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is smashing plates against your friends` door a New Year`s Eve custom?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ski resort is known as the `The Queen of the Dolomites`?",
        "answer": "Cortina, Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you golf the world`s highest elevation championship course?",
        "answer": "La Paz Golf Club, Bolivia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find `The Strand Arcade`, a covered shopping destination?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What countries share a land border with Somalia?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia, Djibouti and Kenya"
    },
    {
        "question": "What three countries share a land border with Somalia?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia, Djibouti and Kenya"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Gulf is located north of Somalia?",
        "answer": "Gulf of Aden"
    },
    {
        "question": "What canal connects Lake Ontario and Lake Erie?",
        "answer": "Welland Canal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What modern day country is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?",
        "answer": "Pharos"
    },
    {
        "question": "The island country Grenada is also known as what?",
        "answer": "Island of Spice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the actual name of the giant human figures of Easter Island?",
        "answer": "Moai"
    },
    {
        "question": "The `Carnac Stones` are located what country?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Long Island Sound separates Long Island from which state?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Angkor Wat temple is featured on what Asian country`s flag?",
        "answer": "Cambodia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation is divided in two by the Cook Strait?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in the world is the longest stretch of straight highway?",
        "answer": "Saudia Arabia -- Highway 10 boasts the longest stretch (140 miles) of completely straight highway in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country does the Amazon River begin?",
        "answer": "Peru -- No fewer than five tributaries have been named as the source over the centuries, but all are located in southwestern Peru."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s only country headed by a Grand Duke?",
        "answer": "Luxembourg -- Since 2000, the role has been fulfilled by Grand Duke Henri of the Nassau-Weilburg family."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Europe`s largest banana farm?",
        "answer": "Iceland -- A banana farm inside a greenhouse in the village of Reykir produces about 1,000 to 4,500 pounds of bananas per year."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the oldest flag in the world?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the International Criminal Police Organization (INTERPOL) headquartered?",
        "answer": "Lyon, France"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states does Yellowstone National Park cover?",
        "answer": "Three -- Wyoming is home to 96% of the park, including the famed Old Faithful geyser, but 1% is in Idaho, and 3% is in Montana."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who created the design for Mount Rushmore?",
        "answer": "Sculptor Gutzon Borglum created the design and oversaw the project`s execution from 1927 to 1941 with his son, Lincoln`s help."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Golden Gate Bridge connects the city of San Francisco with what?",
        "answer": "Marin County -- Many tourist travel across the bridge into Marin County for a view of San Francisco."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country claims the island of Saipan as a commonwealth?",
        "answer": "USA -- Saipan is part of the Northern Mariana Islands, which is a commonwealth of the U.S. Saipan is the seat of the government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s first underwater restaurant?",
        "answer": "Maldives -- The Conrad Maldives Rangali Island hotel is home to Ithaa Undersea Restaurant, which opened in 2005."
    },
    {
        "question": "The second highest mountain on land is K2. What does the letter `K` stand for?",
        "answer": "Karakoram -- K2 is located in the Karakoram Mountain Range."
    },
    {
        "question": "What two nations accompany England and Scotland in the U.K.?",
        "answer": "Northern Ireland and Wales -- Great Britain is comprised of England, Scotland and Wales. Add Northern Ireland to Great Britain to create the U.K."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which major city is located in both Europe and Asia?",
        "answer": "Istanbul -- It is one of only five transcontinental cities in the world. The city straddles the Bosphorus Strait, making its western side European and its eastern side Asian."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Croatia`s famous southern coastline?",
        "answer": "The Dalmatian Coast -- The region is dotted with offshore islands, hidden caves, limestone cliffs, and small, cobblestone towns with Roman ruins."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the world`s first solar-powered bike path?",
        "answer": "The Netherlands -- The country is home to some of the most bicycle-friendly cities in the world and is known as a leader in renewable energy. Built as a prototype, it was removed in November 2020 due to damage."
    },
    {
        "question": "What music festival is held in Manchester, Tennessee each year?",
        "answer": "Bonnaroo -- With up to 80,000 attendees, this multi-day affair features round-the-clock entertainment, with more than 10 performance stages and over 150 performers."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Norwegian krone translates into which English word?",
        "answer": "Crown -- It replaced the speciedaler so that Norway could join Scandinavian Monetary Union with Denmark (Danish krone) and Sweden (Swedish krona), which was dissolved in 1914."
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state is also known as The Golden State?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sea is located between Australia and New Zealand?",
        "answer": "Tasman Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island is Pearl Harbor located on?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Albania?",
        "answer": "Tirana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tirana is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Albania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find `the Hand of the Desert`?",
        "answer": "Atacama Desert, Chile"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hollywood legend Clint Eastwood was once mayor of which city?",
        "answer": "Carmel, California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moraine Lake is found in which National Park?",
        "answer": "Banff National Park, Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what museum will you find Vincent Van Gogh`s painting `The Starry Night`?",
        "answer": "Museum of Modern Art, NYC"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Ayers Rock located?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ruins of the ancient city of Ephesus are located in what present day country?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    }
]